Preliminary Inventory to the Charles Hodges Photographs, 1939-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Hodges Photographs,
1939-1945
64001
Hodges, Charles, d. 1964
54 envelopes (5.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Depicts World War II scenes in Europe, North Africa, the Far East, Southeast Asia, the Pacific Islands, India, and the Aleutian Islands; diplomatic conferences, including the Potsdam Conference, 1945, and the Casablanca Conference, 1943; civilian and military leaders; and maps illustrating military campaigns.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns.; World War, 1939-1945--Peace.; World War, 1939-1945--Pictorial works.
Container List
- Alaska (#1-43) (Folder A)
- Alaska - Alcan Highway (#40-52) (Folder B)
- Argentina (#53-54) (Folder C)
- CBI: Burma liberated (#55-129) (Folder D)
- CBI: Burma - Pipeline (#130-134) (Folder E)
- CBI: Burma Road (#135-187) (Folder F)
- CBI: China - Miscellany (#188-217) (Folder G)
- CBI: China (#218-236) (Folder H)
- CBI: Indochina (#237-257) (Folder I)
- CBI: India (#258-261) (Folder J)
- Conferences I: Potsdam, Berlin, Casablanca (#262-289) (Folder K)
- Conferences II: FDR - Ibn Saud (#290-293) (Folder L)
- Convoy (#294-321) (Folder M)
- ETO: Austria (#322-325) (Folder N)
- ETO: Belgium (#326-355) (Folder O)
- ETO: Czechoslovakia (#356-358) (Folder P)
- ETO: France - Ports (#359-404) (Folder Q)
- ETO: France - Invasions (#405-426) (Folder R)
- ETO: France - Normandy (#427-441) (Folder S)
- ETO: France - Normandy landings (#442-450) (Folder T)
- ETO: France - Paris (and other liberated cities) (#451-472) (Folder U)
- ETO: France - U.S. air operations (#473-501) (Folder V)
- ETO: Germany - Underground factories (#502-505) (Folder W)
- ETO: Germany - Bremen, Cologne, etc. (#506-516) (Folder X)
- ETO: Germany - Middle area (#517-533) (Folder Y)
- ETO: Germany - Rhine (#534-551) (Folder Z)
- ETO: Germany - Hamburg (#552-555) (Folder AA)
- ETO: Germany - Rhine (#556-566) (Folder BB)
- ETO: Germany - Siegfried Line (#567-576) (Folder CC)
- ETO: Germany - Nazi air fields destroyed (#577-579) (Folder DD)
- ETO: Germany - U.S. strategic bombing (#581-597) (Folder EE)
- ETO: Germany - U.S. air operations (#598-626) (Folder FF)
- ETO: Germany - "Wanted for Murder" (#627-643) (Folder GG)
- ETO: Great Britain - Miscellany (no numbers) (Folder HH)
- ETO: Italy, North (#645-678) (Folder II)
- ETO: Italy, South (#679-717) (Folder JJ)
- ETO: Italy-Sicily (#718-739) (Folder KK)
- ETO: Romania - Ploesti (#740-750) (Folder LL)
- ETO: Surrenders (#751-780) (Folder MM)
- Netherlands - East Indies (#781-788) (Folder NN)
- PTO: U.S. air operations - Guadalcanal and Marshall Islands (#789-793) (Folder OO)
- PTO: Japan under attack (#794-832) (Folder PP)
- PTO: U.S. air operations - Japan (#833-860) (Folder QQ)
- PTO: Miniature sets of various Japanese targets produced by the AAF Motion Picture Unit to show American pilots what to bomb (#861-872) (Folder RR)
- PTO: Japan - Surrender on USS Missouri, etc. (#873-946) (Folder SS)
- PTO: U.S. air operations - Philippines (#947-955) (Folder TT)
- North Africa (#956-983) (Folder UU)
- Persian Gulf Command (#984) (Folder VV)
- U.S. Coast Guard (#985-1004) (Folder WW)
- U.S. generals (#1005-1010) (Folder XX)
- U.S. Merchant Marine at war (#1011-1054) (Folder YY)
- WWII - Backwash War - Europe (#1055-1061) (Folder ZZ)
- WWII - Backwash War - Pacific (#1062-1076) (Folder AAA)
- WWII-War maps series (#1077-1098) (Folder BBB)